Deon Hua

deonhua.me github.com/DeonHua deon.hua@uwaterloo.ca

Summary of Qualifications

- Experienced with Python, OOP, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, Git, and JavaScript
- Familiar with AngularJS, C, Flask, Heroku, RESTful design, and Java
- Learning MongoDB, Express, Node.js, Passport, jQuery, Sass, and C++
- · Developed hands-on electronics expertise from experience in labs and competitions
- Excellent communication skills developed from experience presenting programs at the Ontario Science Centre
- Leadership and teamwork skills from time spent as a production leader on numerous highprofile live-performance events

Projects

CampusWall | Web App | MongoDB, AngularJS, Express, Node.js, Passport • A website where students can find and post events happening on campus Personal Website | Website | HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, Materialize • A personal website to showcase my projects Jan. 2015

LinAlg Toolkit | Web App | HTML/CSS, Sass, AngularJS, JavaScript, Flask, Python

Dec. 2014

Reduces and provides properties of matricesComplex number converter and calculator

MolarFast | Web App | HTML/CSS, AngularJS, JavaScript, Flask, Python

Nov. 2014

• A molar mass calculator and temperature converter

WatIsSubletting | Web App | HTML/CSS, AngularJS, JavaScript, Flask, Python

Nov. 2014

 Compares streams of Waterloo students to determine if they can sublet from each other

pyAsteroids | Native | Python, pyGame

May 2013

• The classic arcade game Asteroids, rewritten in Python using OOP

Extra-curricular Activities

Bethune Electronics Club | Founding Executive

Sept. 2013 - June 2014

- Designed and built electrical and electronics projects for the school
- · Competed at the Skills Canada National Competition, finishing third in Canada

Bethune Blaze Audio-Visual Productions | President

Sept. 2010 - June 2014

- Led productions for school and area events, including two annual talent shows
- Toronto District School Board Nexus and Markham's Got Talent

Experience

Ontario Science Centre | Recreational Programs Assistant

Sept. 2013 - Present

• Taught science to children and families in a fun and interesting way

Blank's Media Group | Editor-in-Chief

Apr. 2012 - Present

- A media network that provides technology, gaming, and film content
- Grew the network to over 400,000 views and 34,000 unique visitors

Sir Ernest MacMillan Sr. P.S. | Grade 7 and 8 Mentor/Instructor

Sept. 2010 - June 2014

- Taught students the Scratch and App Inventor programming languages
- Taught students the usage of professional sound and lighting equipment

deonhua.me github.com/DeonHua deon.hua@uwaterloo.ca

Deon Hua

Education

University of Waterloo

Sept. 2014 - Present

- Candidate for Bachelor of Software Engineering
- Roles: Engineering Society Director, Iron Warrior Copy Editor, Engineering Ambassador

Relevant Courses: Introduction to Methods of Software Engineering, Programming Principles

- Learned about memory management and pointers in C
- Developed project and time management methods and techniques

Dr. Norman Bethune C.I.

Sept. 2010 - June 2014

· Received OSSD and graduated with honours

Relevant Courses: Computer Science, Computer Engineering, Electronics Engineering

- Learned Object Oriented Programming techniques and methods in Java and Python
- · Covered data types including linked lists, stacks, and queues

Achievements / Awards

| Dr. Norman Bethune C.I. The A.B. Patterson Award for excellence in technological education The Edge Imaging Award for technical and academic excellence Highest Achievement Award, Grade 12 Computer Science Highest Achievement Award, Grade 11 Electronics Engineering Highest Achievement Award, Grade 11 Computer Science | June 2014 June 2014 June 2014 June 2013 June 2013 |
|--|---|
| Skills Canada Bronze Medal, Skills Canada National Competition – Electronics Gold Medal, Ontario Technological Skills Competition - Electronics Gold Medal, TDSB Electronics Skills Competition Silver Medal, TDSB Electronics Skills Competition | June 2014 May 2014 Mar. 2014 Mar. 2013 |
| University of Waterloo President's Scholarship of Distinction Certificate of Distinction, Canadian Computing Competition (Senior) Gold Standard, Waterloo Hypatia Mathematics Contest | June 2014 Apr. 2014 June 2013 |
| Educational Computing Organization of Ontario Semi-Finalist, ECCO Competition Regional Finalist, TDSB/ECCO Programming Competition | Apr. 2014 Mar. 2014 |
| Purple Comet! Math Meet First place in Canada, High Schools with 1-1200 students | Apr. 2014 |
| The Lifesaving Society • CPR-C With Standard First Aid (Renewed Apr. 2014) | Apr. 2011 |

Interests

• Hackathons, web development, baseball, badminton, environment and renewable energy, analytical writing, animated films, soundtracks, story-driven games